By the end of this year,
بنهاية هذه السنة،
there'll be nearly a billion people on this planet
سيكون هناك حوالي مليار شخص على هذا الكوكب
that actively use social networking sites.
يستعملون الوسائط الإجتماعية بفاعلية.
The one thing that all of them have in common
الأمر الوحيد المشترك بينهم
is that they're going to die.
هو أنهم سوف يموتون.
While that might be a somewhat morbid thought,
وعلى الرغم من أن ذلك قد يكون فكرة رهيبة نوعا ما،
I think it has some really profound implications
أعتقد أن لها آثارا عميقة
that are worth exploring.
تستحق الإستكشاف.
What first got me thinking about this
الآن أول ما جعلني أفكر في هذا
was a blog post authored earlier this year by Derek K. Miller,
هو تدوينة كتبها ديريك ك. ميلر في وقت سابق من هذه السنة،
who was a science and technology journalist
والذي كان صحفيا في مجال العلوم والتكنولوجيا
who died of cancer.
والذي توفي بالسرطان.
And what Miller did was have his family and friends write a post
وما قام به ميلر هو أن جعل عائلته وأصدقاءه يكتبون تدوينة
that went out shortly after he died.
نشرت بعد وفاته بوقت وجيز.
Here's what he wrote in starting that out.
هذا ما كتبه في بداية ذلك.
He said, "Here it is. I'm dead,
قال، "ها أنذا مت
and this is my last post to my blog.
وهذه آخر تدوينة لي على مدونتي.
In advance, I asked that once my body finally shut down
مسبقا، طلبت أنه بمجرد أن يتوقف بدني نهائيا
from the punishments of my cancer,
عن المعاناة من السرطان،
then my family and friends publish this prepared message I wrote --
على عائلتي وأصدقائي أن ينشروا هذه الرسالة الجاهزة التي كتبتها --
the first part of the process
كأول جزء من عملية
of turning this from an active website to an archive."
التحول من موقع فعال إلى أرشيف."
Now, while as a journalist,
الآن، كصحفي
Miller's archive may have been better written
أرشيف ميلر قد يكون كتب بشكل أحسن
and more carefully curated than most,
وأكثر مراعاة من غيره،
the fact of the matter is that all of us today
وحقيقة الأمر هو أننا جميعا اليوم
are creating an archive
نصنع أرشيفا
that's something completely different
وهو أمر مختلف تماما
than anything that's been created
عن أي شيء أنشئ من قبل
by any previous generation.
من قبل أي جيل سابق.
Consider a few stats for a moment.
انظروا إلى بعض الإحصائيات للحظة.
Right now there are 48 hours of video
حاليا هناك 48 ساعة من الفيديوهات
being uploaded to YouTube every single minute.
يتم رفعها إلى يوتيوب في كل دقيقة.
There are 200 million Tweets being posted every day.
هناك 200 مليون تغريدة تنشر كل يوم.
And the average Facebook user
ومستخدم الفيسبوك العادي
is creating 90 pieces of content each month.
ينشئ 90 قطعة من المحتويات في الشهر.
So when you think about your parents or your grandparents,
وبالتالي حين نفكر حول آبائنا أو أجدادنا،
at best they may have created
في أحسن الأحوال قد يكونوا أنتجوا
some photos or home videos,
بعض الصور أو الفيديوهات المنزلية،
or a diary that lives in a box somewhere.
أو مذكرات تعيش في صندوق في مكان ما.
But today we're all creating this incredibly rich digital archive
لكن اليوم يتم إنشاء أرشيفات تقنية في غاية الغنى
that's going to live in the cloud indefinitely,
ستبقى في أنظمة السحاب إلى أجل غير مسمى،
years after we're gone.
سنوات بعد موتنا.
And I think that's going to create some incredibly intriguing opportunities
وأعتقد أن ذلك سينشئ فرصا مثيرة للإهتمام
for technologists.
للتكنولوجيين.
Now to be clear, I'm a journalist and not a technologist,
الآن حتى نكون واضحين، أنا صحفي ولست تكنولوجيا،
so what I'd like to do briefly
وبالتالي ما أود القيام به باختصار
is paint a picture
هو رسم صورة
of what the present and the future are going to look like.
لما سيكون الحاضر والمستقبل عليه.
Now we're already seeing some services
ونحن نرى فعلا الآن بعض الخدمات
that are designed to let us decide
التي صممت لتجعلنا نقرر
what happens to our online profile and our social media accounts
ما الذي سيحصل لملفاتنا الشخصية على الأنترنيت وحساباتنا في الوسائط الإجتماعية
after we die.
بعد أن نموت.
One of them actually, fittingly enough,
أحدها في الواقع، ملائمة تماما،
found me when I checked into a deli
وجدتني حين دخلت إلى دلي
at a restaurant in New York
في مطعم في نيويورك
on foursquare.
في فورسكوير.
(Recording) Adam Ostrow: Hello.
(تسجيل) آدم أوسترو: مرحبا
Death: Adam?
الموت: آدم؟
AO: Yeah.
آ.أ: نعم.
Death: Death can catch you anywhere, anytime,
الموت: الموت يمكن أن يفاجئك في أي مكان، أو زمان،
even at the Organic.
حتى عند مطاعم الأكل العضوي .
AO: Who is this?
آ.أ: من هذا؟
Death: Go to ifidie.net
الموت: اذهب إلى موقع ifidie.net
before it's too late.
قبل أن يفوت الآوان.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Adam Ostrow: Kind of creepy, right?
آدم أوسترو: مخيف نوعا ما، صحيح؟
So what that service does, quite simply,
وبالتالي ما تقوم به هذه الخدمة، بكل بساطة،
is let you create a message or a video
هي أنها تسمح لك بإنشاء رسالة أو فيديو
that can be posted to Facebook after you die.
يمكن نشره على الفيسبوك بعد وفاتك.
Another service right now
خدمة أخرى الآن
is called 1,000 Memories.
تسمى 1,000 ذكريات.
And what this lets you do is create an online tribute to your loved ones,
وما تسمح هذه الخدمة به هو إنشاء إجلال لمن تحبهم على الأنترنيت،
complete with photos and videos and stories
كاملا بالصور والفيديو والقصص
that they can post after you die.
التي يمكن أن ينشروها بعد وفاتك.
But what I think comes next is far more interesting.
لكن ما أعتقده سيأتي لاحقا هو أكثر إثارة للإهتمام.
Now a lot of you are probably familiar with Deb Roy
الآن ديب روي، قد يكون مألوفا لدى الكثير منكم
who, back in March,
الذي، سابقا في مارس،
demonstrated how he was able to analyze more than 90,000 hours of home video.
أظهر كيف كان قادرا على تحليل أكثر من 90,000 ساعة من الفيديوهات المنزلية.
I think as machines' ability
أعتقد أنه وقدرة الآلات
to understand human language and process vast amounts of data
على فهم اللغات البشرية ومعالجة كميات هائلة من البيانات
continues to improve,
تستمر في التحسن،
it's going to become possible
سيصير من الممكن
to analyze an entire life's worth of content --
تحليل مقدار حياة كاملة من المحتويات --
the Tweets, the photos, the videos, the blog posts --
التغريدات والصور والفيديوهات والتدوينات --
that we're producing in such massive numbers.
التي ننتجها بأرقام هائلة.
And I think as that happens,
وأعتقد أنه بحصول هذا،
it's going to become possible for our digital personas
سيصبح ممكنا لشخصياتنا الرقمية
to continue to interact in the real world long after we're gone
أن تستمر في التفاعل في العالم الحقيقي طويلا بعد وفاتنا
thanks to the vastness of the amount of content we're creating
وبفضل ضخامة كمية المحتويات التي ننشئها
and technology's ability to make sense of it all.
والقدرات التكنولوجية لاستيعابها كلها.
Now we're already starting to see some experiments here.
الآن نحن قد بدأنا بالفعل رؤية بعض التجارب هنا.
One service called My Next Tweet
خدمة تسمى تغريدتي التالية
analyzes your entire Twitter stream, everything you've posted onto Twitter,
تحلل كل تدفق التويتر، كل ما نشرته على تويتر،
to make some predictions as to what you might say next.
للتنبؤ بما قد تقوله لاحقا.
Well right now, as you can see,
حسنا حاليا، كما يمكن أن تروا،
the results can be somewhat comical.
النتيجة قد تكون نوعا ما مضحكا.
You can imagine what something like this might look like
يمكنكم تخيل ما قد يبدو عليه هذا
five, 10 or 20 years from now
بعد خمس 10 أو 20 سنة من الآن
as our technical capabilities improve.
مع تطور إمكانياتنا التقنية.
Taking it a step further,
متقدما بخطوة أبعد،
MIT's media lab is working on robots
يشتغل مختبر MIT على روبوتات
that can interact more like humans.
يمكنها التفاعل أكثر مثل البشر.
But what if those robots were able to interact
لكن ماذا لو كانت تلك الروبوتات قادرة على التفاعل
based on the unique characteristics of a specific person
اعتمادا على الصفات الخاصة لشخص معين
based on the hundreds of thousands of pieces of content
اعتمادا على مئات الألوف من أجزاء المحتوى
that person produces in their lifetime?
التي ينتجها المرء في فترة حياته؟
Finally, think back to this famous scene
أخيرا، استرجعوا هذا المشهد الشهير
from election night 2008
من ليلة انتخابات 2008
back in the United States,
سابقا في الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية،
where CNN beamed a live hologram
حين نقلت قناة "سي أن أن" هولوغراما حيا
of hip hop artist will.i.am into their studio
لفنان الهيب هوب will.i.am في ستوديو القناة
for an interview with Anderson Cooper.
للقاء حي مع أندرسون كوبر.
What if we were able to use that same type of technology
ماذا لو أمكننا أن نستخدم نفس نوع التكنولوجيا
to beam a representation of our loved ones into our living rooms --
لإذاعة عرض لأحبائنا في غرف معيشتنا --
interacting in a very lifelike way
في التفاعل بطريقة شبه حية
based on all the content they created while they were alive?
اعتمادا على كل المحتويات المنشأة حين كانوا على قيد الحياة.
I think that's going to become completely possible
أعتقد أن ذلك سيصير في غاية الإمكان
as the amount of data we're producing
وكميات البيانات التي نستخدمها
and technology's ability to understand it
والقدرات التكنولوجية لفهمها
both expand exponentially.
تزدادان معا أسيا.
Now in closing, I think what we all need to be thinking about
الآن في الختام، أعتقد أن ما نحتاج جميعا للتفكير فيه
is if we want that to become our reality --
إن أردنا ذلك أن يصبح حقيقتنا --
and if so,
وإن كان ذلك صحيحا،
what it means for a definition of life and everything that comes after it.
ما يعنيه ذلك لمفهوم الحياة وكل شيء يأتي بعدها.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)